Treasurer's Records, 1982-1994
Smithsonian Institution Archives
Treasurer's Records
1982-1994
Smithsonian Institution Archives, Washington, D.C., osiaref@si.edu
History of Science Society
Non-SI Records
5 cu. ft. (5 record storage boxes)
Accession 98-137
Descriptive Entry
This accession consists of Treasurer's records, and include correspondence, committee minutes and reports, auditors' reports, financial summaries, account activities, Treasurer's reports, budget worksheets, audit and financial statements, journal summaries, and financial data on grants.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following access terms. These are links to collections with related topics, persons or places.
Subject
Professional associations
Physical Characteristics of Materials in the Collection
Clippings; Manuscripts
- Box 1
  - Finances - Pledged Donations, Follow-ups, 1983-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget, 1985 -1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Auditors' Report, 1984-1985 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Coleman, William, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Dauben, J. W., Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Grant, Edward, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Sylla, Edith and Davis, Audrey, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Fund Drive Record and Summary, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Rosenberg, C., Correspondence, 3/1/1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Thackray, Arnold, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, March, 1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Correspondence Other, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Finance Committee and Council, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, Fall 1985 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Addresses, 1983 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget History, 1985-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Auditors' Report, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget, 1986 -1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - IRS, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Coleman, William, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Dauben, J. W., Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Gleason, M. L., Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Grant, Edward, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Rosenberg, Charles, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Nye, Mary J., Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Sylla, Edith, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Thackray, Arnold, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Correspondence Other, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Finance Committee and Council, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, Fall 1986/Spring 1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - End of Year Account Activity, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Fund Drive Summary, 1986-1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Auditors' Report, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Coleman, William, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Neu, John, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Dauben, J. W., Correspondence., 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Nye, Mary J., Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Rosenberg, Charles, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Sokal, Michael, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Sylla, Edith, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Thackray, Arnold, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Weart, Spencer, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Correspondence, Other, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Council and Business Meetings (Raleigh), 1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting (Box 1 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, May 1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Fund Drive Record Summary, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - WPI Financial Statements, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Committee Membership, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Committee on Education, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Committee on Programs and Priorities (Box 1 of 5)
  - Publications Committee, 1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Woman's Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Unaffiliated Scholars Administration, 1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Unaffiliated Scholars, Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Reports and 1987-1988 Budget (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget Worksheets, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
  - Budget and Financial Summaries, 1987-1988 (Box 1 of 5)
- Box 2
  - Chronological File, 1987 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Cash Journals and Accountant's Summaries, 1987-1988 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Year-End Journal and Activity, 1987-1988 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Brush, Stephen G., Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Dauben, J. W., Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Neu, John, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Nye, Mary J., Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Gleason, Mary, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Sokal, Michael, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Weart, Spencer, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Other Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - [Executive Committee], 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Publications Committee Cincinnati (Box 2 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting - Cincinnati, 1988 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Annual Business Meeting, 1988 Cincinnati (Box 2 of 5)
  - Council Meeting - Cincinnati, 1988 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Committee Reports to Executive Committee (Spring 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Budget Preparation, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Budget Background, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - WPI Financial Statements, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - 1989 Meeting (Box 2 of 5)
  - Accounting, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Committee on Education, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Committee on Program and Priorities, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Publication Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Press Proposal for Publishing Journals, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Washington Representative, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Council and Committee Membership, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Manchester Meeting Income/Expense, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Special Meeting Grants, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Non-Pledging Donors (and Pledging), 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Funds Expense, Fund Raising and Promotion, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Audit Reports and Financial Statements, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Year-End Fund and Journal Summaries, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Investments (Box 2 of 5)
  - Audit and Financial Statements, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Chronological File, 1988-1989 (Box 2 of 5)
  - To Be Entered (Box 2 of 5)
  - Chronological File, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Kohler, Frances, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Kohlstedt, Sally Gregory, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Brush, Stephen G., Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Neu, John, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Numbers, Ronald L., Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Nye, Mary Jo, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Sokal, Michael M, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Thackray, Arnold, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Wisconsin Staff, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Other Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - WPI Financial Statements, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - University of Wisconsin Financial Statements, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
  - Penn Budget Considerations and Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 2 of 5)
- Box 3
  - BSHS and Foreign Members, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - 1989 Annual Meeting, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - 1990 Annual Meeting, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting - Madison, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Council Mail Ballots, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting - College Park, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Madison Meeting, 1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Execute Committee Meeting - Gainesville, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Fund Drive Record Summary, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Council Meeting Gainesville, 1989 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Business Meeting Gainesville, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Council and Committee Rosters, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee Reports, 1989 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Publications, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Grants Information, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Programs, 1988-1989/ Columbia Lectures, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - 5-Society Meetings, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee Reports May 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Finance Committee Meetings and Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee Reports (College Park - September 1990), 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee on Education, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee on Publications Madison Meeting, 1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Audit, 1989 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Financial Year - End Summaries and Journals, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Budget Background, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Budget Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Report and Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Chronological File, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Brush, Stephen G., Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Holton, Gerald, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Kohlstedt, Sally G., Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Kohler, Frances, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Myers, Barbara, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Other Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Neu, John, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Numbers, Ronald, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Sokal, Michael, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Stephens Lester D., Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Thackray, Arnold, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Whitrow, Magda, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Pennsylvania Staff, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting - Seattle, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Annual Meeting, 1990 Seattle Meeting (Box 3 of 5)
  - Fund Drive Record Summary, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meetings, 1990-191 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting - College Park, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Council and Committee Rosters, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee Program Expenses, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Report to the Ad Hoc Committee to Review the Office of Executive Secretary, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Report to the Ad Hoc Committee to review Committee Expenses (Weart), 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee on Meetings and Programs, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee on Development Expenses, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Publications Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Committee on Education, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Barbara Myer's Report on HSS Publications, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Grants Information, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Madrid Conference, 1991 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Spencer Weart's Files (Box 3 of 5)
  - Financial Statement, June 30, 1990 (Box 3 of 5)
  - Set-Up Grants Journal, 1991 (Box 3 of 5)
- Box 4
  - 1991-1992
  - Financial Statements, 1991-1992 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Financial Report - Annual Meeting, 1991 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Lounsbery Fund - CoE Grant (Box 4 of 5)
  - Budget Background, 1990-1991 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Executive Committee (Box 4 of 5)
  - Executive Secretary (Box 4 of 5)
  - University Of Chicago Press - History of Science Society (HSS) Agreement (Box 4 of 5)
  - Audit (Box 4 of 5)
  - Committee on Publications (Box 4 of 5)
  - Development Committee (Box 4 of 5)
  - Annual Business Meeting Reports (Box 4 of 5)
  - CoE (Box 4 of 5)
  - Editorial Office (Box 4 of 5)
  - Donations and Gifts (Box 4 of 5)
  - HSS Guide (Box 4 of 5)
  - Kohlstedt, Sally Gregory (Box 4 of 5)
  - Brush, Steven G., Correspondence (Box 4 of 5)
  - Committee Members (Box 4 of 5)
  - Fund Codes - New Views/Bank Accounts (Box 4 of 5)
  - Newsletter (Box 4 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Items (Box 4 of 5)
  - Investments Policy and Actions (Box 4 of 5)
  - Academic Services (Box 4 of 5)
  - Women's Committee (Box 4 of 5)
  - Gleason, Mary Louise, Correspondence (Box 4 of 5)
  - WPI Executive Secretary Office (Box 4 of 5)
  - Editorial Office, Univ. Of Wisconsin (Box 4 of 5)
  - Visiting Historians of Science - Income and Expenditures (Box 4 of 5)
  - Vandergrift, Joan - Isis Editing Consultant (Box 4 of 5)
  - Committee Actions (Box 4 of 5)
  - Committee Reports (Box 4 of 5)
  - Audit - 1991 for (1990-1991) (Box 4 of 5)
  - University Of Chicago Press Negotiations (Box 4 of 5)
  - University Of Pennsylvania - Close-out Publications Office (Box 4 of 5)
  - British Society (Box 4 of 5)
  - Woman's Prize (Box 4 of 5)
  - Executive Secretary Office (Box 4 of 5)
  - Treasurer's Correspondence From, December 1992 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Council, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Executive Secretary, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - President, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Finance Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Executive Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Non-Pledging Donors, 1990-1991 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Audit, 1992-1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 4 of 5)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Audit, 1993 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Quarterly Financial Reports General, Reserve, Endowment, 1993-1994 (Box 4 of 5)
  - Auditor, 1993-1994 (Box 4 of 5)
  - General Fund Committee on Education, 1993-1994 (Box 4 of 5)
- Box 5
  - General Fund Committee on Meetings and Programs (Comp.), 1993-1994 (Box 5 of 5)
  - University of Wisconsin Ledger Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Cornell University Ledger Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Tax Return, 1994-1995 (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF Audit - Preparation Compliance Audit (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF Audit December, 1993 (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF Audit Follow-up Correspondence (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF/NSA Study of HSS and History of Technology (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF Grant - Critical Problems Conference, 1991-1992 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Human Genome Doc. Project (Box 5 of 5)
  - [NSF] (Box 5 of 5)
  - Visiting Historians Correspondence, 1987 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Visiting Historians Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Visiting Historians Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Dibner Visiting Historians Reports (Box 5 of 5)
  - Audit, 1990, 1990-1991 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Ford Foundation, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - General Electric Foundation (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants IBM, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants MacArthur Foundation (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants New York Times Foundation, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Rockefeller, 1985 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Sloan Foundation (Box 5 of 5)
  - Computer Information and Documentation (Box 5 of 5)
  - [NSF - Correspondence, 1988] (Box 5 of 5)
  - NSF Grant - Travel to Manchester (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grant ICHS Travel Grant (Box 5 of 5)
  - Task Force BBS Review, 1990-1991 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Pfizer, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Culpepper, 1983 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Exxon, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Expenses Education Conference Grant, 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grant Proposals, 1987-1988 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Heineman Foundation, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants MacArthur, 1984 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Macy, 1983-1989 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants, 1985: GTE Foundation (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Haas, 1984-1986 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Mellon, 1982 (Box 5 of 5)
  - Grants Sloan, 1985 (Box 5 of 5)